<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.jacalz.rymdport</id>

  <name>Rymdport</name>
  <developer_name>Jacalz</developer_name>
  <summary>Fast, encrypted file transfers</summary>

  <metadata_license>MIT</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>

  <supports>
    <control>pointing</control>
    <control>keyboard</control>
  </supports>

  <description>
    <p>Rymdport (formerly wormhole-gui) is a cross-platform application that lets you easily and safely share files, folders, and text between devices. The data is sent securely with end-to-end encryption using the same protocol as magic-wormhole. This means that Rymdport can talk not only to itself, but also to other wormhole clients.</p>
    <p>The transfers are implemented using wormhole-william, a native Go implementation of magic-wormhole. As a result, Rymdport compiles into a native binary with no runtime dependencies while also outperforming the reference implementation of magic-wormhole.</p>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.jacalz.rymdport.desktop</launchable>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Jacalz/rymdport/main/internal/assets/screenshot1.png</image>
      <caption>Sending Files</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Jacalz/rymdport/main/internal/assets/screenshot2.png</image>
      <caption>Receiving Files</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/Jacalz/rymdport/issues</url>
  <url type="donation">https://github.com/sponsors/Jacalz</url>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/Jacalz/rymdport</url>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

  <!-- Override the kudos that aren't automatically added. See https://gitlab.gnome.org/GNOME/gnome-software/blob/main/doc/kudos.md. -->
  <kudos>
    <kudo>ModernToolkit</kudo>
    <kudo>Notifications</kudo>
  </kudos>

  <releases>
    <release version="3.5.0" date="2023-09-02" type="stable">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Major theme rework with rounded corners.</li>
          <li>Added support for dragging and dropping files and folders onto the application.</li>
          <li>It is now possible to open files or folders in Rymdport from the file manager to start a transfer.</li>
          <li>A transfer can now be started by passing files or folders as command-line arguments.</li>
          <li>Pressing enter after writing a custom code will now start the transfer (#55).</li>
          <li>Instead of giving an error, a number is now added to the end of a file if a duplicate exists (#87).</li>
          <li>Fixed long codes flowing into the progress bar (#96).</li>
          <li>Fixed the QR code showing for failed and completed transfers (#90).</li>
          <li>Refocus the main window after sending text (#85).</li>
          <li>Enabling the option to overwrite files now shows the submit button using a warning colour (#48).</li>
          <li>Fixed a memory leak when starting a second text transfer with the window already open.</li>
          <li>The text send window now opens faster for transfers after the initial start.</li>
          <li>Directory transfers now check that the size and file number are as expected before extraction.</li>
          <li>Long filenames and codes are now truncated using ellipsis instead of clipping.</li>
          <li>Fix text in the progress bar flickering and having the wrong colour sometimes.</li>
          <li>Added an option to disable animations (which can be found within our Settings tab).</li>
          <li>Icons are now installed in more sizes to look better in more places.</li>
          <li>Updated the fyne package to v2.4.0 for many improvements.</li>
          <li>Updated the wormhole-william package to v1.0.7 for minor bug fixes and performance improvements.</li>
          <li>Updated the compress package to v1.16.7 for slightly more efficient compression and decompression of directory transfers.</li>
          <li>Various cleanups and performance improvements throughout the codebase.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
      <url type="details">https://github.com/Jacalz/rymdport/releases/tag/v3.5.0</url>
    </release>
	  <release version="3.4.0" date="2023-06-07" type="stable">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>QR codes can now be generated for easily sending items to supported apps.</li>
          <li>Progress bars no longer display the wrong percentage sometimes.</li>
          <li>Fixed a potential crash that could happen sometimes when sending.</li>
          <li>Added support for removing items that have completed the transfer.</li>
          <li>Added keyboard shortcuts for switching between tabs.</li>
          <li>The receive page now shows which code a received item came from.</li>
          <li>Various improvements to performance and memory usage.</li>
          <li>Updated fyne to v2.3.5 for many bug fixes.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
      <url type="details">https://github.com/Jacalz/rymdport/releases/tag/v3.4.0</url>
    </release>
    <release version="3.3.6" date="2023-05-11" type="stable">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed a crash when pressing the copy button in the text receive window.</li>
          <li>Fixed the AppStream metadata not containing the v3.3.5 release information.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
      <url type="details">https://github.com/Jacalz/rymdport/releases/tag/v3.3.5</url>
    </release>
    <release version="3.3.5" date="2023-05-08" type="stable">
      <description>
        <p>Updated fyne to v2.3.4 for improved performance, less memory usage and 20% smaller binaries.</p>
      </description>
      <url type="details">https://github.com/Jacalz/rymdport/releases/tag/v3.3.5</url>
    </release>
    <release version="3.3.4" date="2023-04-02" type="stable">
      <description>
        <p>Fixed the AppStream metadata not containing the v3.3.3 release information.</p>
      </description>
      <url type="details">https://github.com/Jacalz/rymdport/releases/tag/v3.3.4</url>
    </release>
    <release version="3.3.3" date="2023-03-27" type="stable">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Performance and memory improvements for text rendering.</li>
          <li>Improved performance when resizing the window.</li>
          <li>Fixed letters being cropped in some cases.</li>
          <li>Updated indirect dependencies for some minor security fixes.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
      <url type="details">https://github.com/Jacalz/rymdport/releases/tag/v3.3.3</url>
    </release>
    <release version="3.3.2" date="2023-02-23" type="stable">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Minor performance improvements to the list of sent/received items.</li>
          <li>Updated fyne to v2.3.1 for various bug fixes and improvements.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
      <url type="details">https://github.com/Jacalz/rymdport/releases/tag/v3.3.2</url>
    </release>
    <release version="3.3.1" date="2023-01-28" type="stable">
      <description>
        <p>Minor release to fix Windows binaries not starting. No relevant code changes for Flatpak package.</p>
      </description>
      <url type="details">https://github.com/Jacalz/rymdport/releases/tag/v3.3.1</url>
    </release>
    <release version="3.3.0" date="2023-01-14" type="stable">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Notifications for received files now mentions where the file was saved to.</li>
          <li>Present more useful information about how to write custom codes.</li>
          <li>The dialog for custom codes now focuses the text entry automatically.</li>
          <li>The selection of the download path has been reworked to be more useful.</li>
          <li>Minor redesign of the send and receive tabs.</li>
          <li>Minor wording improvements inside the settings tab.</li>
          <li>The application now uses an entirely new theme with improved visuals.</li>
          <li>The FreeDesktop Dark Style Preference is now respected.</li>
          <li>There is now an option to create a new folder within the folder selection dialog.</li>
          <li>Minor performance improvements for sending and receiving of directories.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
      <url type="details">https://github.com/Jacalz/rymdport/releases/tag/v3.3.0</url>
    </release>
  	<release version="3.2.0" date="2022-07-26" type="stable">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Work around send and receive windows not being focused correctly.</li>
          <li>Go backwards in tab completion using Shift + Tab.</li>
          <li>Update klauspost/compress to v1.15.8 for CVE-2022-30631 fix.</li>
          <li>The zip and completion packages are now exported and considered stable.</li>
          <li>Updated fyne to v2.2.3 for minor bug fixes.</li>
          <li>Minor performance improvements.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
      <url type="details">https://github.com/Jacalz/rymdport/releases/tag/v3.2.0</url>
    </release>
    <release version="3.1.0" date="2022-06-27" type="stable">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Added support for tab completion of receive-codes.</li>
          <li>Notifications now show the application icon.</li>
          <li>The list view in the file chooser now display extensions correctly.</li>
          <li>The entry for receive-codes now unfocuses when pressing escape.</li>
          <li>Various improvements and fixes for the AppStream metadata.</li>
          <li>Notifications are now enabled by default.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
      <url type="details">https://github.com/Jacalz/rymdport/releases/tag/v3.1.0</url>
    </release>
    <release version="3.0.2" date="2022-04-15" type="stable">
      <description><p>Improvements to the AppStream metadata.</p></description>
      <url type="details">https://github.com/Jacalz/rymdport/releases/tag/v3.0.2</url>
    </release>
    <release version="3.0.1" date="2022-04-02" type="stable">
      <description><p>Flatpak support and a performance improvement.</p></description>
      <url type="details">https://github.com/Jacalz/rymdport/releases/tag/v3.0.1</url>
    </release>
    <release version="3.0.0" date="2022-03-07" type="stable">
      <description><p>Major update with lots of improvements and fixes.</p></description>
      <url type="details">https://github.com/Jacalz/rymdport/releases/tag/v3.0.0</url>
    </release>
  </releases>

</component>
